Elijah Melanson

ElijahMelanson@gmail.com | 252-305-1120

Raleigh, NC 27612

Github: /emelanson | LinkedIn: /elijah-melanson-7a966894 | Portfolio: ElijahMelanson.com

Full Stack Web Development | Professional Musician, Audio Engineer, Educator

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer aided by a decade of experience as an internationally-touring musician and educator. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of North Carolina Coding Bootcamp. Brings strength in technical and interpersonal communication, critical thinking ability, and unique vision to each project. Passionate, creative, and deeply interested in creating design-conscious and innovative applications.

Technical Skills (MERN stack)

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL **Applications:** GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Photoshop, Illustrator

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

Projects

Interview Game | Github: https://bit.ly/3azfzdE | Deployed: https://bit.ly/3dvPuyo

- Summary: A multiplayer party word game utilizing websocket to support asynchronous games.
- Role: Full-stack developer
- Tools: JavaScript, Websocket (socket.io), API, Express, Bootstrap, JSON, Heroku

Oversite | Github: https://bit.ly/3pDUTWb | Deployed: https://bit.ly/3pGLc9b

- Summary: A React goal tracking app designed to provide reminders to users based on their goals.
- Role: Full-stack developer
- Tools: React, React-strap, MongoDB, Mongoose, Passport, Hooks, Context API

Experience

Professional Musician (2009-Present) Boston, MA | Raleigh, NC

Guitarist, bandleader, and composer with albums across many genres and hundreds of shows across the US, Europe, and Asia.

- Self-organized tours include festival performances, major talk show (CNN, disko krali, akustikhane) appearances, and club shows in Turkey and France.
- Songwriting, composition, and production credits on more than a half dozen albums.
- Coordinating and booking shows, directing and producing art for releases, and publicizing through social media, independent blogs, newspapers, radio stations.

Private Instructor Raleigh, NC | Boston, MA

(2016-2020): Guitar Teacher, Jazz Band and Music/Production director at Raleigh Community Music School (2009-2016): Teacher at Cary School of Creative Arts, Cary Academy, Independent

- Taught hundreds of students in both private and group settings with a weekly roster size between 20-50 students.
- Mentored students' accomplishments include full-tuition scholarship to Berklee College of Music and successful music careers.

Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development (2021) - University of North Carolina Chapel Hill, NC Coursework towards a BA. in Guitar Performance (2009-2012) - Berklee College of Music Boston, MA